José Hermilo Ortega Martínez

Software Developer

hermilo.jh@gmail.com | (236) 878-1239 | linkedin.com/in/hermilomartinez | hermiloortega.com | Vancouver, BC

Summary

Energetic Software Developer with 6+ years of experience helping companies to reduce time, costs and effort automating processes through high-performance web technologies and implementing advanced methodologies to manage business according to their needs. Team player with a will-do attitude and strong motivation to learn every day.

Work Experience

Web Developer / System Administrator

Epic Inspired (Jul 2020 – Present)

- Work with clients to understand the goals of the website
- Work with select website users to research the needs of people who will use the site
- Work with writers, graphic artists, and programmers to develop or refresh a website
- Communicate the decisions made about how the website will look and work
- Prepare wireframes, design mock-ups and storyboards to show others how the website will look throughout the development process, and get approval
- Develop website sections and how they are organized
- Make decisions on what is needed for the hardware and software
- Organize and outline the content and how visitors will move around the different sections of the website
- Research, develop, and create or buy the content, including photos, graphics, typography, videography and other interactive pieces
- Write content for the website, including labels, micro copy, body copy and help sections
- Design the flow, layout, and look of the website or application
- Plan, design, write, modify, integrate and test website related code
- Test and do other forms of research to make sure the website works for users
- Perform security and quality reviews and generate web analytics
- May lead and co-ordinate teams with different skills and experience to develop the website workflows, content, interface design, graphics, and interactive elements
- May research and review a variety of software, websites, and other interactive/new media.

Team Manager

Spanish Bank East Concession (May 2019 – July 2020)

- Improve the operations time with the implementation of new methodologies in the front desk, kitchen and storage, increase the productivity of employees and teamwork, reducing time lost and disorganization.
- Implemented new methodologies with the management of the food, beverages and products.
- Attention to customers and suppliers to answer questions and solve any complaints.
- Plan, organize, direct, control and evaluate the operations of a restaurant, bar, cafeteria or other food or beverage service
- Determine type of services to be offered and implement operational procedures
- Recruit staff and oversee staff training
- Monitor staff performance
- Control inventory, monitor revenues
- Resolve customer complaints and ensure health and safety regulations are followed
- Negotiate arrangements with suppliers for food and other supplies

Office Administrator

10Star (September 2019 – November 2019)

- Improve the management and control of contracts, events and budgets of the company developing a highquality internal web application implementing new frameworks and methodologies in the process.
- Complete planning, analysis, design, development and execution of the system.
- Conduct analyses and oversee administrative operations related to budgeting, contracting and project planning and management processes
- Assist in preparation of operating budget and maintain inventory and budgetary controls
- Assemble data and prepare periodic and special reports, manuals and correspondence.

Full Stack Software Developer

Altos Hornos de México (June 2013 – December 2018)

- Work with clients to understand the goals of the website
- Work with select website users to research the needs of people who will use the site
- Work with writers, graphic artists, and programmers to develop or refresh a website
- Communicate the decisions made about how the website will look and work
- Prepare wireframes, design mock-ups and storyboards to show others how the website will look throughout the development process, and get approval
- Develop website sections and how they are organized
- Make decisions on what is needed for the hardware and software
- Organize and outline the content and how visitors will move around the different sections of the website
- Research, develop, and create or buy the content, including photos, graphics, typography, videography and other interactive pieces
- Write content for the website, including labels, micro copy, body copy and help sections
- Design the flow, layout, and look of the website or application
- Plan, design, write, modify, integrate and test website related code
- Test and do other forms of research to make sure the website works for users
- Perform security and quality reviews and generate web analytics
- Reduced the time of operations, enforce and money lost of different departments of the company developing more than 10 high-quality and reliable internal software in different platforms.
- Improved the performance of 10 additional internal software previously developed by other developers, implementing new methodologies and algorithms which help in the processing of the information.
- Design and programming of Query used in the database using the best practices.
- Complete planning, analysis, design, development and execution of the system.
- Creation and coordination of reports, policies, formats, system manuals, and meetings.
- End-user support and training to answer questions or solve any issue about systems.

Internship as Junior Software Developer

Altos Hornos de México (June 2011 – December 2011)

 Helped create and improve efficient and reliable internal website to show the agreements and benefits to employees with city businesses

Education

Master's Degree in Software Engineer	
Instituto de Estudios Universitarios (Puebla, México)	
Master's Degree in Leadership and Management	
Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science	j
Instituto Tecnológico Superior de Monclova (Coahuila, México)	